神秘博士
2011 Comic Relief 喜剧短片
空间
编剧：魔法特
嘿
Hey.
听好 我们能谈谈吗
Listen, can we talk?
罗瑞
ROREEEY!
别闹 闭嘴 我就一个问题
No. Shut up. I've just got a question, that's all.
没我什么事了吧
You OK up there?
对 很好 没问题
Yeah, fine, no problem.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
给博士帮忙呢
Helping the Doctor.
它在嗡嗡响 这正常吗
It's humming, is that OK?
没事 我们正在进入概念空间
Yeah, it's fine. We're just entering conceptual space.
想象一根香蕉 或任何弧形的东西
Imagine a banana or anything curved
实际上 算了
Actually, don't.
因为它并不是弧形 也不像香蕉
since it's not curved or like a banana
别管香蕉了
Forget the banana!
他在帮你开塔迪斯吗
Er, is he helping you fly the Tardis?
把2号7号和11号热电偶装上
Attach thermo-couplings two, seven and eleven.
按我教你的做
like I showed you.
他怎么能操作 你从来没让我试过
How come he gets to have a go? You never let me have a go.
博士
Er, Doctor,
说
Go.
说真的 我让她开过一次我的车
Seriously, I let her drive my car once.
切 才到路口而已
Yeah, to the end of the road.
但是 据艾米描述
Well, According to Amy
"一栋房子突然冒出来了"
there was an unexpected house.
他嫉妒了 因为我的驾照一次就考过了
He's jealous because I passed my test first time.
你作弊 你穿了条短裙
You cheated. You wore a skirt.
我才没有穿短裙
I didn't wear a skirt.
没穿效果也一样
Well, That would have worked too.
不对 我确实穿了条短裙
No, no, I did wear a skirt.
但只是一条普通的旧短裙而已
But it was any old skirt.
你见过艾米开车没有 博士
Have you ever seen Amy drive, Doctor?
没有
No.
她的驾照考官也没有
Neither did her driving examiner.
实际上就是这条 就是这条裙子
Actually, it was this one. It was this skirt.
什么情况
What was that?
罗瑞 你是不是把电偶掉地上了
Rory, did you drop a thermo-coupling?
对不起
Sorry.
你怎么能这样 我说过多少遍
Argh. How did you do that? I told you,
不要弄掉 亏我还特地强调过的
don't drop them. I specifically mentioned not dropping.
这是我的错
It was my fault.
这当然不是你的错
Of course, it wasn't your fault.
确实有点是她的错
It kind of was her fault.
怎么又成她的错了
How could it be her fault?
因为我的短裙 我的丈夫 和你的透明地板
Because it was my skirt and my husband and your glass floor.
噢 罗瑞
Oh, Rory.
对不起喽
Sorry.
我们已经着陆了
Well, we've landed.
有紧急显形装置 应该没大碍
Emergency materialization. Should be fine.
已经锁定最安全的可及空间
Should have locked onto the safest space available.
博士 这是什么情况
Doctor, what's happened?
最安全的可及空间
Safest spot available.
塔迪斯显形在自己内部了
The TARDIS has materialised inside itself.
这算正常情况吗
Is that supposed to happen?
你觉得呢
Take a guess.
不正常
No.
答对了
That's the one.
那么 你要怎么办
Well, what are you doing?
完全没有头绪
Absolutely no idea
好吧 这确实有点诡异
Oh oh. OK, That's a bit weird
实际上 我觉得挺酷的
That is actually pretty cool.
很高兴你觉得有趣 罗瑞
I'm glad you're entertained, Rory,
这下我们要永远困在这儿了
Now that we're stuck here for all eternity
至少你不会觉得无聊
at least you won't be bored.
等等 什么 我们被困住了
Wait! What? We're stuck?
现在塔迪斯的内部连着外部
The inside of the TARDIS is now joined to the outside of the TARDIS
比时间循环还要糟糕 这是空间循环
Worse than a time loop, a space loop.
谁也不能再进入或离开这艘飞船了
Nothing can enter or leave this ship ever again.
好了 孩子们 现在事情开始变得复杂了
OK, kids, this is where it gets complicated.
你到底是什么人
Who the hell are you?
时间
编剧：              魔法特
我是你 来自未来的你
I'm you... from your future
确切的告诉我到底发生了什么
Tell me exactly what's happened.
好的 塔迪斯的外部时间向未来偏移了
Well, the exterior shell of the TARDIS has drifted forwards in time.
如果你现在走进去的话
If you step into the box now
你就会进到塔迪斯几分钟前的控制室
you step inside the control room a tiny bit into the past.
我没听懂
I don't understand.
我也不懂
Neither do I.
但是你刚说出来的啊
But you just said it.
不 我只是复述而已
No, I'm just repeting it.
我只是记得站在你那里时
I'm just remembering what I heard myself saying
听到自己说的话 然后重复而已
when I was standing where you are standing now, and repeting it.
这句也是重复
I'm just repeting this, too.
这句也是…还有这句
And this ... and this.
呃 我还是搞不懂
Oh, I still don't understand.
你还是不懂
You still don't…
行了 这位艾米是什么时候走进塔迪斯的
OK, when does this Amy step into the box?
我们得保持时间线连贯才行
We need to maintain the timeline.
噢 就在她扇了罗瑞一巴掌之后
Ah. As soon as she's slapped Rory.
好的
OK
哼 想得美 凭什么我要被扇
Huh. No, why do I get slapped?
因为我们必须遵守已经形成的
Because we have to stick to
一系列相关联的循环事件
the established chain of events.
一旦出差错 整个时间线就会…崩溃
One mistake and the whole timelime could collapse.
到时候就得永远守着两个艾米·庞德
We'll end up with two Amy Ponds forever,
然后你怎么办
and then what would you do?
好了 你 快到警亭里面去
OK, you, into the Policebox, now.
然后我就变成她了
And then I become her?
没错 该闪了 快闪
Yes. Go, go, go!
我真的长这个样子吗
Do I really look like that?
没错 就是这个范儿
Yeah. Yeah, you do.
这样见考官 什么驾照都秒杀
I'd give you a driving license.
那是当然的了
I bet you would.
噢 结局真相大白
Oh, this is how it all ends
庞德和自己调情 终于找到了真爱
Pond flirting with herself ! True love at last.
噢 抱歉 罗瑞
Oh... Sorry, Rory.
我没有任何意见
Absolutely no problem at all.
现在 艾米
Now, Amy.
第一句是什么来着
What's the first line?
好了 孩子们 现在事情开始变得复杂了
OK, kids, this is where it gets complicated.
明白了
Gotcha.
然后呢 就这样吗 我们没事了吧
So, is that it? Are we OK now?
没完 还困在这儿呢
No, we're still trapped.
你们干什么
What are you doing?
是你叫我们走进警亭的
You told us to get into the police box.
从你的角度来说
Well, from your point of view
你马上要叫我们走进警亭了
you're about to tell us to get into the police box.
从我的角度来说 你刚刚叫我们走进警亭
From our point of view, you just told us to get into the police box
所以我们就走进了警亭
which is why we got in the police box
于是就来到了这里
which is why we're here.
这一长串的话我全都得记住吗
Do I have to remember all of that?
好像自然而然就发生了
It just sort of happens.
嗨
Hi.
别闹了
Stop that!
你们俩 到警亭里去 快跑
You two, into the police box now. Run.
那现在呢
So. What now?
你们两个 原地不动
You two stay where you are.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我要建立一个临时可控内爆装置
I'm setting up a controlled temporal implosion.
只有这样才能重置塔迪斯
It's the only way to reset the TARDIS
但前提是我知道哪个是正确的操纵杆
But unless I find exactly the right lever to control the implosion,
不然我们就死定了
we're all gonna die.
你不知道是哪个操纵杆
You don't know which lever.
不知道 但是我马上就要知道了
No. But I'm about to find out.
Wibbly操纵杆
The wibbly lever!
The wibbly lever.
谢了
Thank you!
很好 我们又回到正常航行了
Okay, we're back in normal flight.
塔迪斯也不在自己内部了
The Tardis is no longer inside itself,
局部时间场也不会再内爆
the localised time field is no longer about to implode
也不会把时空撕出裂缝了
and rip a hole in all causality
但是 为了以防万一
But just in case,
庞德 找条裤子穿上
Pond, put some trousers on.